The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
So I brought a few problems.
所以我带来了一些问题。
They're obviously not the quiz problems, though some of them
他们显然不是测验问题，尽管其中一些
are supposed to be similar.
应该是相似的。
What I have here might not be what
我在这里可能不是
you have on the quiz because we might drop quiz problems
您参加测验，因为我们可能会放弃测验问题
or because some of them are just meant to make
或者因为其中一些只是为了
you think and not to give away the solutions to the quiz.
您会思考而不是放弃测验的解决方案。
Now, before we get started on this,
现在，在我们开始之前，
do you guys have any burning questions or any concepts
你们有什么迫切的问题或概念吗
that you want covered?
你想要覆盖？
Based on that, I'll select which problems we do.
基于此，我将选择我们要解决的问题。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: This actually relates not too much to the Pset.
听众：这实际上与Pset没有太大关系。
If you're looking at the time complexity
如果您正在查看时间复杂性
to maybe transfer something from one table to another,
可能将某物从一张桌子转移到另一张桌子，
it takes a lot more time, I would
我要花很多时间
assume, to move the actual item to the new table
假设将实际项目移动到新表
than it does just to look at your point and be like,
不只是看你的观点而变得像
oh, there's nothing there.
哦，那里什么都没有。
So if you were just going to look
所以，如果你只是想看看
through an empty table of size m,
通过一个大小为m的空表，
the time to look through that empty table, I'm assuming,
我假设是时候浏览那个空表了，
is much less than the time to actually move an item.
比实际移动项目的时间少得多。
PROFESSOR: So you're saying we have m things here.
教授：所以您是说我们这里有m东西。
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Some might be nil, and some
教授：有些可能为零，有些则为
might have stuff in them, and you're
里面可能有东西，而你
going to resize that to presumably 2 times m,
要将其大小调整为大约2倍，
and the way you do that is you're
而你这样做的方式就是
going to move the elements, presumably by rehashing them,
要移动这些元素，大概是通过重新哈希它们，
right?
对？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: So these elements, at least when we use Python,
教授：所以这些要素，至少在我们使用Python时，
we don't really store big elements anywhere.
我们并没有在任何地方存储大型元素。
If you have a big object, we always
如果您有大物件，我们总是
work with references to that object.
使用对该对象的引用。
So you remember the address where
所以你记得地址
that object lies in memory, and since the memory is
该对象位于内存中，并且由于内存是
finite and small, addresses are all from 0 to a small number,
有限和较小，地址都从0到一个小数，
so they're constant.
所以他们是不变的。
So what you have here is not a big object.
因此，您在这里拥有的并不是一个大对象。
It's the address of the big object,
这是大物件的地址，
so moving is always constant time.
因此移动始终是恒定的时间。
AUDIENCE: What I'm saying is let's
听众：我的意思是让我们
say that the table is completely full
说桌子已经满了
versus completely empty table.
与完全空表。
It would take more time to move everything out
将所有内容移出将花费更多时间
of the full table than it does just
整个表的大小
to look the empty table, right?
看空桌吧？
PROFESSOR: Let's see.
教授：让我们看看。
So writing something here is order 1 time, right?
所以在这里写东西是命令1次，对吗？
So moving is order 1 time.
因此，移动是订购1次。
Moving one element is order 1 time.
移动一个元素是命令的1倍。
What's accessing an element in a table in a list?
什么正在访问列表中表中的元素？
You have a Python list.
您有一个Python列表。
What's the cost of doing an index access?
进行索引访问的成本是多少？
AUDIENCE: It's also order 1, right?
听众：这也是命令1，对吗？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So order 1, index.
因此，顺序1，索引。
Order 1, move.
顺序1，移动。
Suppose you have an empty table.
假设您有一个空表。
How many indices do you do?
您做多少指数？
How many times the index?
索引多少次？
AUDIENCE: You look at each one, so it's
听众：你看着每一个，所以
order 1 times the length of the table.
订购表长度的1倍。
PROFESSOR: m.
教授：
So if the table is empty, you have order m indices
因此，如果表为空，则您有m个索引
and 0 moves.
和0移动。
Total running time, order m.
总运行时间，订购m。
If you have a full table, how many times
如果您有一张完整的桌子，多少次
do you index in the table?
你在表中索引吗？
AUDIENCE: Still order m.
听众：还订购m。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
How many times do you move stuff?
您将东西移动多少次？
AUDIENCE: Order m.
听众：订单m。
PROFESSOR: Total running time?
教授：总运行时间？
AUDIENCE: It's order 2m, which is order m.
听众：2m订单，m订单。
PROFESSOR: So it doesn't matter whether the table's
教授：所以桌子的
full or empty.
满或空。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
Just wanted to confirm that.
只是想确认一下。
PROFESSOR: And this is how you do that.
教授：这就是您的做法。
Cool.
凉。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Then we will go over problems in the order in which I like them,
然后，我们将按照我喜欢它们的顺序来解决问题，
which is easiest to hardest so that I
最容易到最难的是
don't have to explain the hard ones.
不必解释那些困难的事情。
Warm up problem one.
热身问题一。
So you have this recursion and you have to solve it,
因此，您需要进行递归处理，并且必须解决它，
and you get a hint that n to the power of 1 over log n
并且您得到一个提示，即n大于n的n为1的幂
is 2, which is theta 1.
是2，即theta 1。
So based on the hint, you can see
因此，根据提示，您可以看到
that it's going to involve some math.
这将涉及一些数学。
It's going to get a bit ugly.
这将变得有点丑陋。
So how do we solve recursions?
那么我们如何解决递归呢？
Two methods.
两种方法。
What are they?
这些是什么？
AUDIENCE: Expand.
听众：扩大。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Substitution formally, but basically, we
正式替代，但基本上，我们
expand this guy over and over again.
一遍又一遍地扩大这个家伙。
And?
和？
AUDIENCE: Trees.
听众：树木。
PROFESSOR: Recursion trees.
教授：递归树。
Which one do guys want to do first?
伙计们想先做哪一个？
If you only have one t here, anything
如果这里只有一吨
works because you can keep expanding it and that works,
之所以有效，是因为您可以不断扩展它，而且有效
so we can do either method.
所以我们可以做任何一种方法。
Which one do you guys want to go over?
你们想跳过哪一个？
Trees.
树木。
OK.
好。
So we start with the first node.
因此，我们从第一个节点开始。
The size of the problem is n.
问题的大小是n。
What's the cost inside here?
这里的费用是多少？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So this creates one sub-problem.
因此，这产生了一个子问题。
What's the size?
什么大小
AUDIENCE: n to the 1/2.
听众：n到1/2。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Square root of n equals n to the 1/2.
n的平方根等于n的1/2。
You solved it already.
您已经解决了。
What's the cost?
费用是多少？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: Do people remember this?
教授：人们还记得吗？
Is anyone confused about what's going on here?
有人对这里发生的事情感到困惑吗？
OK.
好。
So two terms, something involving t and something
所以两个词，涉及t和某些
not involving t.
不涉及t
The thing involving t is what we want to get rid of.
涉及t的东西是我们要摆脱的东西。
When we do our recursion tree, whatever is in here
当我们做递归树时，这里有什么
goes inside here, and this tells me
走进这里，这告诉我
how this number relates to this number.
该数字与该数字的关系。
So when I go from one level to the next level,
所以当我从一个级别转到另一个级别时，
this is the transformation.
这就是转变。
n and becomes square root of n, so the transformation here
n并成为n的平方根，所以这里的变换
is the same as the transformation here.
与此处的转换相同。
What's next?
下一步是什么？
AUDIENCE: n to the 1/4.
听众：n为1/4。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Cost?
成本？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Do we need to do one more or do people see the pattern?
我们是否需要再做一遍，还是人们看到了这种模式？
Silence means one more.
沉默意味着更多。
If you guys don't speak, we're going to go slow.
如果你们不说话，我们会变慢的。
What's here?
这是什么
AUDIENCE: n to the 1/8.
听众：n到1/8。
PROFESSOR: What's here?
教授：这是什么？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: Let's hope everyone saw the pattern,
教授：希望大家看到了这种模式，
and suppose we've done this for l levels,
并假设我们已经完成了l个级别，
so we're at the bottom.
所以我们在最底层。
What should the cost be at the bottom?
最低成本应该是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Sorry.
教授：对不起。
We don't start with the cost.
我们不是从成本开始的。
What should the size of the problem be at the bottom?
问题的大小应该在底部？
AUDIENCE: n to the 1 over 2 to the i.
受众：n比1多2。
PROFESSOR: Let's say that this is
教授：可以说这是
level h, where h is the height of the tree.
级别h，其中h是树的高度。
AUDIENCE: Don't you want to do something like n to the 1
听众：您是否不想对1做n
over n?
超过n？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
OK, so we want something that looks like that?
好吧，所以我们想要看起来像这样的东西？
AUDIENCE: If the recursion tree is height i,
听众：如果递归树是高度i，
it is n to the 1 over 2 to the i, but 2 to the i
n等于1等于2的i，但2等于i
should equal n, or approximately n.
应该等于n或大约n。
PROFESSOR: Why?
教授：为什么？
I like that, but why?
我喜欢，但是为什么呢？
AUDIENCE: Because you need to go down
听众：因为你需要下去
until you're only looking at one element,
直到您只看一个元素，
and that would be one nth of the problem.
那将是问题的十分之一。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we want this guy to look like what?
所以我们希望这个家伙看起来像什么？
In fact, it doesn't exactly have to look like 1, but what's
实际上，它不一定非要像1，而是
the advantage if we manage to get this guy to look like 1?
如果我们设法让这个家伙看起来像1的优势？
We have a recursion.
我们有一个递归。
We don't have a base case here, right?
我们这里没有基本情况，对吗？
A reasonable base case is T of 1 is theta 1.
一个合理的基本情况是T等于1等于theta 1。
Whatever function that is, if you evaluate it at 1,
不管是什么函数，如果将其评估为1，
you're going to get a constant, so you can say that.
您将获得一个常数，所以可以这样说。
Now, at the same time I can say that for any constant,
现在，我可以同时说对于任何常数，
c, T of c is theta 1.
c，c的T为theta 1。
So if I take this constant here, which happens to be 2,
所以如果我在这里取这个常数，恰好是2
but that's not to worry about that.
但这不用担心。
If I take this guy here, I can put it in here.
如果我把这个人带到这里，我可以把它放在这里。
And I know that this guy here equals this guy here.
我知道这里的人等于这里的人。
So if I can make this guy here look like this guy here,
所以，如果我可以让这个人看起来像这个人，
then I'm done.
那我就完成了
Make sense?
说得通？
If it makes sense, everyone should nod so
如果有道理，每个人都应该点头
that I know and I can go forward, or smile or something.
我知道，我可以前进，或者微笑或其他。
So this should look like 1.
所以这看起来应该像1。
This is order 1 if not 1.
如果不是1，则为订单1。
Let's make it order 1, because it's 2 in this case.
让我们将其设为1，因为在这种情况下为2。
What's the cost here?
这要花多少钱？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: 1.
教授：1。
Everything inside the bubbles is order of already,
气泡内的所有东西已经是顺序，
so I don't need to write an order of.
所以我不需要写命令。
What do we do next?
接下来我们要做什么？
AUDIENCE: Solve the [INAUDIBLE] equation.
听众：求解[听不清]方程。
2 to the [INAUDIBLE].
2转到[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: You're skipping one step.
教授：您跳过了一步。
That's exactly what you do when you have the substitution
这就是替换后的工作
method.
方法。
You're going to get to something and you
你要去做某事，你
need to solve the equation.
需要解方程。
But for the tree, there are two steps.
但是对于树，有两个步骤。
So we need to add up all the costs here
所以我们需要在这里加总所有费用
and that's the total cost here.
这就是这里的总费用。
In order to do that, first, we sum up over each level.
为了做到这一点，首先，我们对每个级别进行总结。
And in this case, it's really simple
在这种情况下，这非常简单
because there's only one node per level,
因为每个级别只有一个节点，
but if you have multiple nodes per level,
但是如果每个级别有多个节点，
you have to sum up for each level,
您必须总结每个级别，
and then you have to do a big sum.
然后你必须做一个大数目。
What's the sum for this level?
这个级别的总和是多少？
1.
1。
Come on, guys.
拜托了伙计们。
You're scaring me.
你吓到我了。
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
AUDIENCE: It's all 1.
听众：全都是1。
PROFESSOR: Excellent.
教授：非常好。
So the only thing that I'm missing
所以我唯一想念的是
is to know how many levels I have, because the sum is going
知道我有多少个水平，因为总和
to be order h, whatever h is.
不论h是多少，都可以成为h的阶。
How do we do that?
我们该怎么做？
n to the 1 over 2 to the power of h
n等于2的1的幂
has to equal this guy, right?
必须等于这个家伙，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Why would it equal that guy?
听众：为什么这等于那个家伙？
We know it's less than that guy, but we
我们知道这比那个家伙少，但是我们
don't know it's equal to that guy.
不知道那等于那个家伙。
PROFESSOR: We have to make it equal because we can only
教授：我们必须使其平等，因为我们只能
stop when we get to the base case.
当我们到达基本情况时停止。
So we have to expand the recursion tree
所以我们必须扩展递归树
until we get to a base case, and then we stop,
直到我们找到一个基本案例，然后我们停止，
and this is our base case because this
这是我们的基本情况，因为
is what the problem says should be our base case.
问题是我们的基本情况。
AUDIENCE: Right, but n to the 1 over 2 to the h
听众：是的，但是n等于1等于2等于h
is not equal to n to the 1 over log n.
不等于n等于对数n的1。
PROFESSOR: Well, we can set h to be whatever we want.
教授：好吧，我们可以将h设置为我们想要的任何值。
h is the height of the tree, so we don't know what it is.
h是树的高度，所以我们不知道它是什么。
We have to find out what it is.
我们必须找出它是什么。
AUDIENCE: So let's say 2 to the h
听众：让我们对小时说2
is equal to log n if you want to make it look like that.
如果要使它看起来像log n，则等于。
PROFESSOR: Let me write down the equation
教授：让我写下等式
to make sure you're right.
确保你是对的。
You're probably right because you're thinking faster than me,
您可能是对的，因为您的思考速度比我快，
but let me not embarrass myself and do this the right way.
但是让我不要让自己感到尴尬，并以正确的方式做这件事。
So you said 2 to the h is log n, right?
所以你对h说2是log n，对吗？
Looks about right.
看起来不错。
So what's h?
那是什么？
AUDIENCE: Log base 2.
受众：日志基数2。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
Log log n.
日志日志n。
So T of n is order h.
因此，n的T为h阶。
We got this from here.
我们从这里得到的。
T of n is order h is order of log log n.
n的T是阶h，是log log n的阶。
Math people drowning, right?
数学人淹死了，对吗？
Any questions about this?
对此有任何疑问吗？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: The first line on the right--
听众：右边的第一行-
PROFESSOR: This?
教授：这吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
Is that your base case?
那是你的基本情况吗？
What is that?
那是什么？
PROFESSOR: We got a hint with the problem that said,
教授：这个问题我们得到了提示，
n to the power of 1 over log n is 2, which is order 1.
n在log n上的1的幂是2，即1阶。
So for the base case, we always want them to look like this.
因此，对于基本情况，我们始终希望它们看起来像这样。
If we don't get a base case, we write our own base case,
如果没有基本案例，我们将编写自己的基本案例，
which is if you plug in a constant,
如果您插入一个常数，
you're going to get a constant.
您将获得一个常数。
And since we're told that this guy is a constant,
由于我们被告知这个家伙是一个常数，
that's a pretty good hint that we want to get to it.
这是我们想要实现的一个很好的暗示。
Let's see how we're doing on time.
让我们看看我们的准时情况。
Good.
好。
Ready to move on to the next problem?
准备继续下一个问题了吗？
Let's do a fun one.
让我们做一个有趣的。
Some people might remember it from elementary school,
有些人可能记得上小学时
but this time, we're going to look at it with our 6.006 eyes.
但是这次，我们将以6.006的眼睛进行观察。
So suppose you have m coins, gold coins.
因此，假设您有m个硬币，金币。
One of them is face.
其中之一是脸。
The fake one is super light because it's not real gold.
假货是超轻的，因为它不是真金。
It's something that looks like gold.
它看起来像金子。
And we have a scale, and the scale is super accurate.
而且我们有一个秤，并且秤超级准确。
It can weigh any coins on either side
它可以在任一侧称重任何硬币
and tell us which side is heavier.
告诉我们哪一边更重
Perfect accuracy, no need to worry about errors.
完美的准确性，无需担心错误。
I want to find out which coin is the bad coin.
我想找出哪个硬币是坏硬币。
What is the minimum number of experiments I have to do?
我最少必须进行多少次实验？
So there is a strategy, and we can worry about that later,
因此，有一个策略，我们稍后可以担心，
but using 6.006, what is the minimum number of experiments
但是使用6.006，最少需要进行多少次实验
I have to do?
我要做？
AUDIENCE: Log N times.
听众：登录N次。
PROFESSOR: Not quite.
教授：不完全是。
So this is what you think is, and you
所以这就是你的想法，而你
can do log n with binary search, right?
可以用二进制搜索登录n，对吗？
The problem with binary search is if I put half of my coins
二进制搜索的问题是，如果我将一半硬币投入
on the left, half of my coins on the right,
在左边，我一半的硬币在右边，
one side is going to be heavier, right?
一侧会更重吧？
So the answers are going to be this or this,
所以答案将是这个或这个，
but I never get this.
但我从来没有得到这个。
I only get one bit of information
我只得到一点信息
instead of getting one trit.
而不是一无所获。
A trit is a base three digit.
Trit是基数的三位数。
How many bits of information in a trit?
Trit中有多少位信息？
AUDIENCE: One and a half.
听众：一年半。
PROFESSOR: Roughly.
教授：大概吧。
AUDIENCE: Log 3.
听众：登录3。
PROFESSOR: Log 3.
教授：日志3。
And we know that it's base 2 because that's
而且我们知道这是基数2，因为那是
what we use in CS.
我们在CS中使用的内容。
So we're discarding a fractional bit of information
因此，我们正在丢弃一小部分信息
if we're not allowing for this to happen.
如果我们不允许这种情况发生。
Anyone want to try something else?
有人要尝试其他吗？
We have to prove this, by the way.
顺便说一下，我们必须证明这一点。
We have to prove the minimum that we come up with.
我们必须证明我们提出的最低要求。
AUDIENCE: You could just do it coin by coin,
听众：您可以逐个硬币地做，
but that would take forever.
但这将永远。
PROFESSOR: That's N. That's worse.
教授：那是N。更糟。
AUDIENCE: How about log base 4 N or something like that?
听众：以4 N为底的对数怎么样？
AUDIENCE: Can you explain to me why we can't just
听众：你能告诉我为什么我们不能只是
do binary search?
进行二进制搜索？
PROFESSOR: We can.
教授：我们可以。
It's definitely going to give us the correct answer,
肯定会给我们正确的答案，
but it's not the minimum number of weighings
但这不是最小称量数
because we're discarding a possible answer.
因为我们正在放弃可能的答案。
So if you do binary search, you will never
因此，如果您执行二进制搜索，您将永远不会
get that the two sides are equal.
得到双方平等。
AUDIENCE: Log base 3.
听众：日志基数3。
PROFESSOR: Log base 3 would be better
教授：以3为底的日志会更好
because we have three choices all the time.
因为我们一直都有三个选择。
Let's prove that.
让我们证明这一点。
So the right answer happens to be log base 3 of N. Let's see
因此正确的答案恰好是N的对数底数3。
how we would get it aside from guessing.
我们如何从猜测中除掉它。
AUDIENCE: So you divide it into thirds
听众：所以你把它分成三份
and compare one third and one third, and if they're equal,
并比较三分之一和三分之一，如果相等，
then the light one is in the other third.
那么光一个在另一个三分之一。
And if they're not, [INAUDIBLE] light one.
如果不是，请[听不清]。
Then you just keep dividing by 3.
然后，您只需除以3。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So that's the strategy.
这就是策略。
What if I don't know the strategy?
如果我不知道该怎么办？
How do I do this without knowing the strategy?
在不知道策略的情况下该如何做？
AUDIENCE: What if the number of coins isn't divisible by 3?
观众：如果硬币的数量不能被3整除怎么办？
PROFESSOR: Math people.
教授：数学人。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, but then how do you-- OK, never mind.
听众：是的，但是那你怎么样了-好吧，没关系。
AUDIENCE: Just take the two extra coins and toss them out.
听众：只需多拿两个硬币，然后扔掉。
PROFESSOR: If it's not divisible by 3,
教授：如果不能被3整除，
you add fake coins that are good.
您添加好硬币。
I mean, you use good coins.
我的意思是，您使用优质的硬币。
But we're not worried about the strategy.
但是我们并不担心该策略。
I want us to think of a lower bound.
我希望我们想到一个下限。
This is a lower bound for an algorithm, right?
这是算法的下限，对吗？
You cannot do better than log 3 N experiments.
您不能做得比记录3 N实验更好。
Does the word "lower bound" ring any bells?
“下界”一词响起吗？
Is there any lecture where we talked about lower bounds?
有没有关于下界的讲座？
So if you sort and you're using a comparison model,
因此，如果您进行排序并使用比较模型，
what's the best you can do?
你能做的最好的是什么？
AUDIENCE: N log N.
听众：N logN。
PROFESSOR: N log N. Good.
教授：N logN。
So sorting using CMP, the comparison model, is N log N.
因此，使用比较模型CMP的排序为N logN。
How did we prove that?
我们如何证明这一点？
One word.
一个词。
Well, two words.
好吧，两个字。
Decision trees.
决策树。
Does anyone remember what decision trees are?
有谁记得决策树是什么？
One person.
一个人。
AUDIENCE: It's just a comparison thing, right?
听众：这只是比较，对吗？
You're like, is it greater, is it less than,
您就像是，它大于，还是小于，
or is there some sort of question
还是有什么问题
you're asking about each key.
您正在询问每个键。
PROFESSOR: Cool.
教授：太好了。
Let's go over that a little bit.
让我们再谈一点。
No matter what your algorithm is,
不管您的算法是什么
it's going to weigh some coins and it's
它会重一些硬币，
going to get an answer from the scale.
从天平上得到答案。
And then based on that, it's going to weigh some other coins
然后基于此，它将权衡其他一些硬币
and get some answer from the scale.
并从规模中得到一些答案。
And it will do some experiments and then
它会做一些实验，然后
it will give you an answer.
它会给你答案。
So if you draw a decision tree, it would look like this.
因此，如果您绘制决策树，它将看起来像这样。
First, we start with 0 information.
首先，我们从0信息开始。
We weigh some coins.
我们称重一些硬币。
Based on that, we have three possible answers--
基于此，我们有三个可能的答案-
smaller, equal, greater.
较小，相等，较大。
Now, if we're here, we're going to do another experiment.
现在，如果我们在这里，我们将做另一个实验。
Three possible answers.
三个可能的答案。
If we're here, another experiment, three possible
如果我们在这里，另一个实验，三个可能的
answers.
答案。
If we're here, another experiment, three possible
如果我们在这里，另一个实验，三个可能的
answers.
答案。
Say we do a third experiment.
假设我们做了第三个实验。
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three, one,
一，二，三，一，二，三，一，二，三，一，
two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three, one, two,
二，三，一，二，三，一，二，三，一，二，
three, one, two, three, one, two, three.
三，一，二，三，一，二，三。
And then suppose we stop.
然后假设我们停止。
If we stop, we have to give an answer.
如果我们停下来，我们必须给出答案。
So this is an answer, this is an answer,
所以这是一个答案，这是一个答案，
this is an answer, answer, answer, answer, answer, answer.
这是一个答案，答案，答案，答案，答案，答案。
So how many answers do I have at the bottom
所以我在底部有多少个答案
if I have three levels?
如果我有三个级别？
Here I have three experiments, so three levels
这里我有三个实验，所以三个层次
in the decision tree.
在决策树中。
How many answers?
有多少个答案？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: 3 to the third because I start three
教授：从三到三，因为我从三开始
at the first level, nine at the second, 27 at the third.
在第一级，第二级为九，第三级为27。
Each time, I multiply by 3.
每次，我乘以3。
So if I do three weighings, I can give at most 27 answers.
因此，如果我进行三次称重，则最多可以给出27个答案。
If I have more than 27 coins, I can't possibly
如果我有27个以上的硬币，我就不可能
decide which one is bad because say if I have 30 coins,
确定哪一个不好，因为如果我有30个硬币，
then I need to be able to give out 30 answers.
那么我需要给出30个答案。
My algorithm has to have a place where
我的算法必须有一个地方
it says the bad coin is coin one, coin two, coin three, all
它说坏硬币是硬币一，硬币二，硬币三
the way to coin 30.
硬币投币方式30。
Here I only have 27 possible answers,
在这里，我只有27个可能的答案，
so this isn't going to cut it for 30 coins.
所以这不会减少30个硬币。
I need to do one more comparison so that I have a deeper tree.
我需要再进行一次比较，以便获得一棵更深的树。
So suppose I have h comparisons instead.
因此，假设我有h比较。
How many leaves?
几片叶子？
How many possible answers?
有多少可能的答案？
AUDIENCE: h to the third.
听众：h至第三。
PROFESSOR: Almost.
教授：差不多了。
AUDIENCE: 3 to the h.
听众：3至h。
PROFESSOR: 3 to the h.
教授：3至h。
So 3 multiplied by 3 multiplied by 3 multiplied by 3 h times,
所以3乘3乘3乘3小时，
so 3 to the h.
所以3到h。
It's no longer equal to 27.
它不再等于27。
3 to the h is the number of possible answers.
h的3表示可能的答案。
This has to be bigger or equal to N. Otherwise,
该值必须大于或等于N。否则，
the algorithm is incorrect.
该算法不正确。
So what can we say about h?
那么关于h我们能说什么呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: We did all this without even thinking
教授：我们做这一切都没有想到
of what an algorithm would look like.
算法的外观。
This works for any algorithm.
这适用于任何算法。
No matter how smart you are, no matter how much math you know,
不管你有多聪明，无论你知道多少数学，
your algorithm is going to be bound by this.
您的算法将受到此约束。
So the fact that the answer looks like this
所以答案看起来像这样
gives you some intuition for how to solve the problem.
给您一些解决问题的直觉。
If you want to solve the problem now and figure out
如果您现在想解决问题并找出答案
the strategy, you know that you have a 3 here.
策略，您知道这里有3。
So if you divide into 2 every time,
因此，如果您每次均分为2，
you're not going to get to the right limit.
您将无法达到正确的极限。
So first you do this, you get a lower bound,
所以首先您要执行此操作，您将获得一个下限，
and then you use your intuition to figure out
然后你凭直觉找出
what the lower bound means.
下界是什么意思。
In this case, it would mean the strategy that we heard earlier.
在这种情况下，这将意味着我们之前听到的策略。
You have to divide into 3 every time
每次都要分成三份
and then figure out what you do based on the comparison.
然后根据比较找出您要做什么。
So your answer works perfectly once we have this.
因此，一旦我们有了这个，您的答案就会非常有效。
And also, once we have this, you know
而且，一旦我们有了这个，您就会知道
that your answer is correct because it's optimal.
您的答案是正确的，因为它是最佳的。
You can't do better than that.
你不能做得更好。
Any questions on decision trees?
对决策树有任何疑问吗？
So lower bounds are a boring topic in general.
因此，下限通常是一个无聊的话题。
They tell you what you can't do.
他们告诉你你不能做什么。
They don't tell you anything useful about what you can do.
他们没有告诉您有关您可以做什么的任何有用信息。
In some cases, being able to reason about a lower bound
在某些情况下，能够推理出下限
gives you a hint of the solution.
给您提示解决方案。
New problem.
新问题。
Suppose we have a 2D map.
假设我们有一个2D地图。
There's a hill, and you take a satellite picture of it
有一座小山，你为它拍了卫星照
at night, and you get a picture with bright pixels and not
到了晚上，您得到的图像像素明亮而不是
bright pixels.
明亮的像素。
There are numbers showing how bright your pixels are.
有数字显示像素的亮度。
1, 2, 1, 2, 3, 0, 0.
1、2、1、2、3、0、0。
I'm going to draw out an example so we can use our intuition.
我将举一个例子，以便我们可以运用直觉。
0, 0, 1.
0、0、1。
So suppose this is our map.
因此，假设这是我们的地图。
It's W times H-- W of what these are,
这是W乘以H–W，
I think they're columns, and H of the other ones.
我认为它们是列，而其他列是H。
And you want to find a certain picture inside it.
您想在其中找到特定的图片。
You want to see how many times does a certain pattern show up.
您想查看某个模式显示多少次。
Say the pattern is small w times small h,
假设模式是小w乘小h，
and it looks like this.
看起来像这样
But this will be the input to your problem,
但这将是您的问题的输入，
so the pattern might be different.
因此模式可能会有所不同。
You can't hard code this in.
您不能对此进行硬编码。
And this is useful.
这很有用。
This problem is called a bunker hill problem.
这个问题称为邦克山问题。
This is a hill, and this is a bunker.
这是一座小山，这是一个掩体。
You take a picture of the hill.
你给山拍张照片。
You want to know where the bunkers are
你想知道掩体在哪里
so you can bomb them at night so then you can attack the place.
所以你可以在晚上炸弹，然后再攻击该地方。
AUDIENCE: That's awful.
听众：太可怕了。
PROFESSOR: Thank you.
教授：谢谢。
I'll take that as a compliment So a nice way of solving this?
我会称赞一下，那么解决这个问题的好方法吗？
AUDIENCE: You could just go through each row,
听众：您可以逐行浏览，
and then look for a match for the first row, and then--
然后寻找第一行的匹配项，然后-
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Is this a match?
这是火柴吗？
That's what you're saying.
那就是你的意思
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
We can see that's a match.
我们可以看到这是一场比赛。
PROFESSOR: Is this a match?
教授：这是比赛吗？
Is this a match?
这是火柴吗？
By the way, this is a match.
顺便说一句，这是一场比赛。
This is not a match, this is not a match, this is not a match,
这不是比赛，这不是比赛，这不是比赛，
this is not a match.
这不是比赛。
Now we go down here.
现在我们去这里。
This is not a match, this is not a match,
这不是比赛，这不是比赛，
this is not a match, so on and so forth.
这不是匹配项，依此类推。
AUDIENCE: That wasn't what I was suggesting,
听众：这不是我的建议，
but that's a good idea.
但这是个好主意。
PROFESSOR: Maybe you're suggesting something smarter,
教授：也许您是在建议一些更聪明的东西，
and I don't want to let you do something
我不想让你做某事
smarter so that we look at the brute force approach first.
更聪明，因此我们首先来看一下蛮力方法。
AUDIENCE: I mean, I was just saying
听众：我的意思是，我只是说
take the first row of your bunker,
进入沙坑的第一排，
and then compare it to other rows,
然后将其与其他行进行比较
and once you hit that, then check and see if the rest of--
然后当您击中该点后，再检查一下是否
PROFESSOR: Yeah, that's a bit smarter,
教授：是的，这有点聪明，
so that's harder to reason about.
所以这很难推理。
Let's take this one and figure out the running time of it.
让我们来看看它的运行时间。
AUDIENCE: Does that mean even if you know it's not a match,
听众：这是否意味着即使您知道这不是比赛，
you keep checking all nine of them?
您一直检查所有九个？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Say at the worst case, you only find out
说最坏的情况，您只会发现
it's not a match all the way at the end.
并不是一路走到尽头。
AUDIENCE: Are you trying to look for all matches or just one?
观众：您是要寻找所有匹配项还是只寻找其中一项？
PROFESSOR: All matches.
教授：所有比赛。
AUDIENCE: You're limited to n squared time almost no matter
听众：几乎无论如何，您都限于n平方时间
what, right?
什么，对不对？
If you have a small bunker in a large field,
如果您在大片土地上有一个小型掩体，
you have to hit the small bunker every time.
你每次都要打小沙坑。
PROFESSOR: Are you going to solve the problem for me?
教授：您要为我解决问题吗？
AUDIENCE: Are we trying to find the [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：我们是否在寻找[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
We're trying to find out the running
我们正在尝试找出运行情况
time for the dumb algorithm first.
首先是愚蠢算法的时间。
Humor me and let's solve this first,
幽默我，让我们先解决这个问题，
and then let's get to the efficient algorithm, OK?
然后我们来看看高效的算法，好吗？
AUDIENCE: Big W minus small w plus 1 times big H
受众群体：大W减去小w加上大H的1倍
minus small h plus 1.
减去小h加1。
AUDIENCE: Where'd you get plus 1 from?
听众：您从哪里获得加号1？
AUDIENCE: So it's WH?
听众：是吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Well, there's something missing here.
教授：好吧，这里缺少一些东西。
This is how many positions I have that I have to look at.
这是我要看的几个职位。
How much time does it take to compare the small images?
比较小图像需要多少时间？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: This is smaller than wh, which is the input size,
教授：这比输入大小wh小，
so it's scary if you have an algorithm that runs faster
因此，如果您有一种运行速度更快的算法，那将很可怕
than the input size because it means
比输入大小大，因为这意味着
you're not looking at all the input.
您并没有查看所有输入。
So this is definitely bigger than the input size
所以这绝对大于输入大小
once we add the w times h here.
一旦我们在这里加上w乘以h
Don't forget this guy.
别忘了这个家伙。
This is the naive algorithm, and if we discard the small order
这是幼稚的算法，如果我们抛弃小阶
factors, we get that this is order of WHwh.
因素，我们得到这是WHwh的顺序。
How can you do better?
你如何做得更好？
You have the answer, right?
你有答案吧？
Let's let everyone else think for a minute,
让其他人思考一下，
and then you can give me the answer if you want,
然后，如果需要，您可以给我答案，
or someone else can give me the answer.
否则其他人可以给我答案。
I guess you should because you thought of it first.
我想您应该因为首先想到它。
Any ideas?
有任何想法吗？
So you're thinking about the input size, right?
所以您正在考虑输入大小，对吗？
Someone was thinking about the input size.
有人在考虑输入大小。
So the input size is W times H, right?
所以输入大小是W乘以H，对不对？
So if I have an algorithm that's W times H,
因此，如果我的算法是W乘以H，
that's optimal because it has to look at all the input.
这是最佳选择，因为它必须查看所有输入。
Well, we're going to have an algorithm that's
好吧，我们将要有一个算法
W times H, so with that out of the way,
W乘以H，因此，
does that inspire anyone as to what the solution is?
这是否会激励任何人解决方案？
AUDIENCE: Do that thing that I was saying,
听众：照我说的做，
just take the first row, but then you still have a W term.
仅取第一行，但您仍有W项。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So let's make it better.
因此，让我们做得更好。
It is the correct intuition.
这是正确的直觉。
Now try to use a trick we learned in lecture to make that
现在尝试使用我们在讲座中学到的技巧来使
faster.
快点。
AUDIENCE: Just use the top left corner
听众：只需使用左上角
instead of the whole row.
而不是整行。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we could use the top left corner,
所以我们可以使用左上角
and if the top left corner doesn't match,
如果左上角不匹配，
then we don't have to check for matches.
那么我们就不必检查匹配项。
So this works for reasonably random data.
因此，这适用于合理的随机数据。
As long as we don't have a lot of false positives,
只要我们没有很多误报，
we're going to run fast.
我们将快速运行。
Now, the top corner of this one, if the map
现在，这个地图的顶角
has a lot of 1's and then some 2's sprinkled all over it,
有很多1，然后在上面撒了2，
most of the time, we'll have to go through the whole image
大多数时候，我们必须仔细检查整个图像
so we're going to have a lot of false positives.
所以我们会有很多误报。
How do we make our false positive rate go down?
我们如何使误报率下降？
AUDIENCE: Looks kind of like a rolling hash problem.
听众：看起来有点像滚动哈希问题。
PROFESSOR: Looks like a rolling hash problem, exactly.
教授：确实看起来像一个滚动的哈希问题。
Let's see if we can use rolling hashes.
让我们看看是否可以使用滚动哈希。
AUDIENCE: But then you still have that lowercase w
听众：但是那时候你仍然有那个小写字母w
term, though.
学期。
PROFESSOR: How do we get rid of it?
教授：我们如何摆脱它？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: Wouldn't it be w?
听众：不是吗？
I mean the running time if we were just going through one row
我的意思是说如果我们只经过一排的话
would be big W minus little w, times--
W大减去小w
PROFESSOR: So where's your rolling hash?
教授：那您的滚动哈希值在哪里？
AUDIENCE: I guess you can use the entire thing as a hash,
听众：我想您可以将整个内容用作哈希，
too.
太。
That would kind of work.
那样的工作。
PROFESSOR: So we want a hash for the whole thing.
教授：因此，我们希望对整个过程进行哈希处理。
Instead of using this as the hash, we want a smarter hash.
与其使用它作为哈希，我们不希望使用更智能的哈希。
AUDIENCE: It's the entire thing, and then
听众：这是整个过程，然后
as you move to the right, you can add those and subtract,
向右移动时，您可以将其相加并减去，
and compare that with the hash.
并与哈希进行比较。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we'd have a rolling hash that has everything in here,
因此，我们将拥有一个滚动式哈希，其中包含所有内容，
and then as I move to the right, I add these guys
然后当我向右移动时，我添加了这些人
and I remove these guys.
我将这些人撤职。
This is big W times big H, roughly, times small h
这是大W乘以H，大约是小h
because every time I move to the right,
因为每次我向右移动时
I have to do order h work.
我必须命令工作。
So I'm down from this thing to order of WHh,
所以我从这件事降到了WHh的等级，
So it's better.
这样更好。
It's one step forward.
这是前进的一步。
Now, let's make this even faster.
现在，让我们更快。
What if I could do this in order 1 instead of order h?
如果我可以按顺序1而不是顺序h怎么办？
How would I do this in order 1?
我将如何在订单1中进行此操作？
AUDIENCE: You'd have to compress all the rows,
听众：您必须压缩所有行，
and then take the hash of each column.
然后获取每一列的哈希值。
PROFESSOR: How would we compress them?
教授：我们将如何压缩它们？
AUDIENCE: Take the hash of the column.
受众：取列的哈希值。
PROFESSOR: You want to compress the rows?
教授：您要压缩行吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
You divide it--
你把它分开
PROFESSOR: Let's not compress the rows.
教授：我们不要压缩行。
AUDIENCE: You could take just your bunker,
听众：你可以只带掩体，
and then figure out the hashes of the three columns,
然后找出三列的哈希值
and just run through like that.
然后就这样跑
You'd still have to access each of those items.
您仍然必须访问所有这些项目。
I don't really see how it's faster.
我真的不知道它有多快。
I guess it's less, though.
我想这要少一些。
It's less.
少一些
Maybe it's only 1.
也许只有1。
AUDIENCE: So do you want to hash each little column [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：那么您是否想对每个小列进行散列[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: So we're going to hash all these guys,
教授：因此，我们将对所有这些人进行散列，
and then we're going to have hashes for them,
然后我们要为它们散列
and we're going to do the regular Rabin-Karp
我们将定期进行Rabin-Karp
for the hashes.
散列。
Now, what happens when I go down?
现在，当我下去时会发生什么？
PROFESSOR: You have to recompute everything.
教授：您必须重新计算所有内容。
PROFESSOR: Let's do better than recompute everything.
教授：让我们做得比重新计算一切还要好。
AUDIENCE: Do you want to [INAUDIBLE] downward
听众：您想向下[听不清]
on each column?
在每列上？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Rolling hash.
滚动哈希。
I want to make this faster, so I have big W hashes.
我想使其更快，所以我有很大的W哈希值。
They're all little h inside.
他们都在里面。
Here, I have to compute them brute force.
在这里，我必须计算它们的蛮力。
I can't do anything better.
我再好不过了。
But when I go from here to here, there's
但是当我从这里到这里时，
only one element going out and one element going in.
只有一个元素进入而一个元素进入。
Same for all these guys.
所有这些家伙都一样。
Let's not make the picture uglier than it needs to be.
让我们不要使图片更丑陋。
So I have big W rolling hashes.
所以我有很大的W滚动哈希。
They're vertical rolling hashes.
它们是垂直滚动的哈希值。
And then the rolling hashes hash columns, so my the sliding
然后滚动散列哈希列，所以我滑动
window that I have is little w rolling hashes.
我拥有的窗口很少滚动哈希值。
Each rolling hash is little h in size, so it's a hash of hashes.
每个滚动哈希的大小都为h，因此它是哈希的哈希。
It's nested hashes.
它是嵌套的哈希。
And then when I go down, I only have
然后当我下去时，我只有
to roll down each of the rolling hashes by 1,
将每个滚动哈希值滚动1，
so that's constant time.
所以那是恒定的时间。
So to go from here to here, to the slide the window one down,
因此，要从此处移至此处，将窗口向下滑动一次，
I have to roll this hash down, roll this one,
我必须把这个哈希值滚下来，把这个哈希值滚下来，
this one, this one, this one, this one, and all of them
这个，这个，这个，这个和所有这些
roll down in constant time.
在恒定的时间内滚下来。
So when I'm adding a column to the hash, say I'm here
因此，当我在哈希中添加一列时，说我在这里
and I want to go here, I roll down this hash
我想去这里，我把这个哈希值滚下来
and I have the answer.
我有答案。
It's order 1.
订单1。
I'm adding it in order 1.
我将其按顺序添加1。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
AUDIENCE: It's tricky.
听众：这很棘手。
PROFESSOR: But it's not too bad, right?
教授：但这还不错，对吗？
AUDIENCE: You just need to do the vertical roll first, right?
听众：您只需要先进行垂直滚动，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
To have the simplest possible code,
要获得最简单的代码，
you start with big W rolling hashes, do 1D Rabin-Karp,
从大的W滚动哈希开始，进行一维Rabin-Karp，
you roll everything down, 1D Rabin-Karp,
你放下一切，一维Rabin-Karp，
and keep doing that.
并继续这样做。
OK What's the running time for this?
好的，这是什么时间？
AUDIENCE: WH.
听众：WH。
PROFESSOR: WH.
教授：WH。
AUDIENCE: Does this one have a space complexity about W, then,
听众：这是否具有关于W的空间复杂度，然后，
because [INAUDIBLE]?
因为[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So my memory requirement went up to 4W.
所以我的内存需求上升到4W。
Is everyone happy with this?
每个人都满意吗？
It's one of the few cases where an approach for solving a 1D
这是少数解决一维问题的方法之一
problem generalizes to 2D.
问题普遍适用于2D。
In most problems, you have to rethink the whole situation.
在大多数问题中，您必须重新考虑整个情况。
Let's do a hard problem.
让我们做一个困难的问题。
Enough with the easy ones.
够简单的了。
Two lists, roughly size N, and they're both sorted.
两个列表，大小大致为N，并且都已排序。
Let me fill them out with random numbers.
让我用随机数填写它们。
5, 13, 22, 43, 56, 62, 81, 86, 87, 2, 3, 7, 9, 15, 19,
5、13、22、43、56、62、81、86、87、2、3、7、9、15、19，
24, 28, 32.
24、28、32。
So I have these lists.
所以我有这些清单。
Let's be generous and say that all the numbers are different.
慷慨地说，所有数字都不一样。
They're sorted.
他们已排序。
I want to find the nth number, so the number with rank n,
我想找到第n个数字，所以排名为n的数字，
out of both lists as fast as possible.
尽快从两个列表中删除。
AUDIENCE: Wouldn't it just be index?
听众：不仅仅是索引吗？
PROFESSOR: So the thing is if, for example, n is 1,
教授：那么，例如，如果n为1，
then it's this.
就是这个
This is the second number.
这是第二个数字。
This is the third.
这是第三。
So if you take the lists and you combine them,
因此，如果您将列表合并在一起，
then I want the result out of that.
那么我想要结果。
AUDIENCE: Let's do merge sort and the combined
听众：让我们进行合并排序和合并
[INAUDIBLE] index, right?
[音频不清晰]索引，对不对？
PROFESSOR: Full merge sort, N log N?
教授：完全合并排序，N对数N？
No.
没有。
AUDIENCE: It's already sorted, though.
听众：虽然已经排序了。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So what do we do?
那么我们该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: We just do merge.
听众：我们只是合并。
That's just order N.
那只是命令N。
PROFESSOR: So merge.
教授：所以合并。
AUDIENCE: Merge [INAUDIBLE].
听众：合并[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So merge and then index is the first approach,
因此，合并然后索引是第一种方法，
which is order N. Then you said run the merge algorithm,
这是N阶。然后您说运行合并算法，
but stop when you get to the little nth element,
但是当您到达第n个小元素时就停下来，
so that's a little bit better and we don't have
所以好一点了，我们没有
to produce an array so the space complexity is down to order 1,
产生一个数组，使空间复杂度降至1阶
right?
对？
Now let's do--
现在开始
AUDIENCE: Logarighmic times n.
听众：对数乘以n。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, exactly.
教授：好的。
This is linear.
这是线性的。
We have to get to logarithms.
我们必须对数。
How do we get to logarithms?
我们如何获得对数？
AUDIENCE: Do a modified binary search.
听众：进行修改后的二进制搜索。
AUDIENCE: What if you first looked at-- actually,
观众：如果您初次看过-实际上，
I don't know what I'm going to say.
我不知道我要说什么。
PROFESSOR: Anyone else?
教授：还有其他人吗？
So modified binary search.
因此修改了二进制搜索。
Do you know the full answer, or do you
您知道完整的答案吗？
want to start looking at the solution?
想开始寻找解决方案？
AUDIENCE: I have an idea [INAUDIBLE].
听众：我有一个主意[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Let's see how it would work.
教授：让我们看看它是如何工作的。
AUDIENCE: So if we take the n over second element
观众：所以如果我们把n放在第二个元素上
on each row, the one that is lower,
在每一行中，较低的那一行
that's at least the n over second element,
至少是第二个元素的n
and the one that's higher--
还有更高的那个
PROFESSOR: So let's say this is our N1 and N2,
教授：那么我们说这是我们的N1和N2，
and they're both order N initially.
他们最初都是N。
So this is N2 over 2 if this is smaller.
因此，如果N2小于2，则为N2。
AUDIENCE: The lower one is at least
听众：较低的至少是
the N over second element since everything
第二个元素以来的N
before it is less than N. Does that make sense?
在小于N之前。这有意义吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So this is N over 2 are greater, right?
所以N大于2是吧？
This guy.
这家伙。
AUDIENCE: We also know that the element above it
观众：我们也知道上面的元素
is at most the nth element because it's greater than--
最多是第n个元素，因为它大于-
PROFESSOR: So it's at most N1 plus N2
教授：所以最多是N1加N2
because that's how many you have in total,
因为那就是你总共有多少
and the one on the top, you know that these ones are
和最上面的那个，你知道这些是
bigger than h, right?
比h大吧？
But you don't know anything about these ones,
但是你对这些一无所知
so it's minus N1 over 2.
所以是N1减去2
So it's at most N1 over 2 plus N2, the top element.
所以最多是N1超过2加上N2，即最上面的元素。
AUDIENCE: So then we can take the element three quarters
听众：那么我们可以将元素占四分之三
of the way through N2 and one quarter of the way
通过N2的方式和方法的四分之一
through N1 to do more [INAUDIBLE].
通过N1做更多[听不清]。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：[听不清]？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Let's see what happens in each case.
教授：让我们看看在每种情况下会发生什么。
So if little n is here, then you divide.
因此，如果小n在这里，则除法。
So if n is smaller than this, then you chop them up here
所以如果n小于这个，那么就把它们切成小块
and you've divided the problem into half.
并且您将问题分成了一半。
You're good.
你很厉害。
If it's bigger than this other number here,
如果比这里的其他数字大，
you've chopped the problem up and you're here.
您已经解决了问题，就在这里。
You're good.
你很厉害。
Now, the hard case seems to be when it's in between.
现在，最困难的情况似乎是在两者之间。
So what do we do then?
那我们该怎么办呢？
AUDIENCE: Aren't those two numbers the same?
听众：这两个数字不一样吗？
AUDIENCE: If it's between, take the upper half
听众：如果介于两者之间，则取上半部分
of the bottom one and the lower half of the upper one, right?
底部的一半和上面的一半的下半部分，对吗？
If it's between 15 and 43, then you take everything
如果介于15到43之间，则一切
in the upper half of N2 and you take the lower half of N1.
在N2的上半部分，而您在N1的下半部分。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, you should always
听众：是的，你应该总是
be taking the upper half of one and the lower
取一个的下半部分和下一个
half of the other in this case.
在这种情况下，另一半。
PROFESSOR: Really?
教授：是吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] N2, 15 is at least
观众：[听不清] N2，至少15
the nth over 2 element.
2个元素中的第n个。
I think we're using three n's at the same time.
我认为我们同时使用三个n。
AUDIENCE: Are you using the little n or the big N?
听众：您使用的是小N还是大N？
AUDIENCE: Sorry.
听众：对不起。
[INAUDIBLE] is element and the lists are called N
[INAUDIBLE]是元素，列表称为N
and this is confusing.
这令人困惑。
Can we rename the nth element to something
我们可以将第n个元素重命名为某种东西吗
like m or some other useful number?
像m或其他有用的数字？
The kth element, OK.
第k个元素，确定。
So the 15 at least the kth over 2 element,
因此，至少15个元素超过2个元素，
so it can't be anything on the left half of the--
所以它不能放在左半部分
PROFESSOR: k over 2?
教授：k超过2？
Why k over 2?
为什么k超过2？
This list is size N.
此列表的大小为N。
AUDIENCE: Sorry.
听众：对不起。
I didn't pick the elements at N over 2.
我没有在2以上的N中选择元素。
I picked the elements at k over 2.
我在2以上的k处选取了元素。
PROFESSOR: Why would I do that?
教授：我为什么要这样做？
If N1 is greater than k, then I chop off the end of the list,
如果N1大于k，则我将列表的末尾切掉，
right?
对？
If N2 is bigger than k, then I chop off the end of the list
如果N2大于k，则将其切掉
completely.
完全。
If this list is sorted and I want the third element,
如果此列表已排序并且我想要第三个元素，
I know that these are not the answer.
我知道这些不是答案。
No matter what's down here, these are not the answer.
无论这里发生了什么，这些都不是答案。
So I know for sure that k is going to be bigger than N1, N2.
因此，我确定k将大于N1，N2。
So instead of going there, let's go at k over 2.
因此，让我们而不是去那里，让我们超过2。
And here, let's go for k over 2.
在这里，让我们在2上求k。
Now this one looks a bit nastier.
现在，这个看起来有点不舒服。
N1 plus N2 stays what it was before.
N1和N2保持以前的状态。
AUDIENCE: On the list where you got the element that was lower,
观众：在清单上您得到较低的元素，
you know that everything to the left of it is less than k
你知道它左边的所有东西都小于k
over 2.
超过2。
The element number is lower than k over 2,
元素数小于k大于2，
so we're not using anything to the left of the 15.
所以我们在15号左边不使用任何东西。
You can kill that section for us.
您可以为我们杀死该部分。
PROFESSOR: OK, so we can kill it, but then what's the rank?
教授：好的，我们可以杀了它，但是等级是多少？
When I recurse, how am I going to know
当我递归时，我怎么知道
the rank that I'm looking for?
我要寻找的排名？
AUDIENCE: k minus what you killed.
听众：k减去您杀死的内容。
AUDIENCE: You can save the branches.
听众：您可以保存分支。
PROFESSOR: So you want to kill this guy, right?
教授：所以你想杀了这个家伙，对吗？
So you want to kill these numbers.
所以您想杀死这些数字。
But here I have k over 2 numbers,
但是这里我有k个超过2个数字，
and here I have k over 2 numbers.
这里有2个以上的k
How do I know that it's not somewhere here?
我怎么知道它不在这里？
AUDIENCE: How do you know that what's not somewhere there?
听众：您怎么知道那里没有什么？
AUDIENCE: You compare 15 and 43, right?
听众：您比较15和43，对吗？
And then you see that 43 is bigger,
然后您看到43更大，
and you see 15 is smaller, so then you would go to, I guess,
然后您会看到15较小，所以我想
k over 4 index in N1, and 3k over 4 in N2.
N1中k大于4的索引，N2中4大于3k的索引。
AUDIENCE: When you recurse, you said
听众：当您递归时，您说
that you've killed k over 2 elements.
您已经杀死了2个元素中的k个。
AUDIENCE: But you can also kill everything to the right of 43.
听众：但您也可以杀死43岁右边的所有人。
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
You can kill everything to the right of 43
您可以杀死43右边的所有东西
since it can't be any of those elements,
由于不可能是任何这些元素，
and you can kill everything to the left of 15.
然后您可以杀死15号左侧的所有内容。
And then you repeat the algorithm again with the lists
然后使用列表再次重复该算法
you didn't kill, except you also put in a term of we've
您没有杀人，除了您还输入了
already covered k over 2 elements.
已经覆盖了2个元素中的k个。
PROFESSOR: So we want the element with the rank k over 4
教授：所以我们希望k大于4的元素
over these lists.
在这些列表上。
So I know for sure that what I have is either k over 2
所以我确定我所拥有的要么是k大于2
or less than k over 2, right?
或小于2的k，对吧？
So this is less than k over 2, and then I'm
所以这是小于2的k，然后我是
looking for a rank of k over 4.
寻找超过4的k。
That seems to work.
这似乎有效。
How does the running time look?
运行时间如何？
AUDIENCE: It should be O of log k.
听众：应该是log k的O。
AUDIENCE: I think it's log [INAUDIBLE].
观众：我认为这是[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: So log k, log N1 plus N2.
教授：所以记录k，记录N1加N2。
Are these different?
这些不同吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: If k is 1, the algorithm
听众：如果k为1，则算法
should only recurse once, even if N is 20 million.
即使N为2,000万，也只应递归一次。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: But if k is 20 million and the list lengths are
听众：但是如果k为2000万且列表长度为
two million long, it'll take approximately those lengths
200万长，大约需要这些长度
to run.
跑步。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So what gets reduced, aside from the list size, k gets reduced.
因此，除列表大小外，k减少了。
k seems to define the input size for the next iteration
k似乎定义了下一次迭代的输入大小
because I'll have at least k over 2 elements in one
因为我至少要在一个元素中包含2个以上的k个元素
of these buckets.
这些水桶中。
So it sounds like it should be log k.
因此，听起来应该是log k。
k is bigger than N1, N2, but it should hopefully be smaller
k大于N1，N2，但希望它应小于
than the sum because otherwise, why am I doing the problem?
比总和要大，因为否则我为什么要这样做？
So this is definitely order of N1 plus N2.
因此，这绝对是N1加N2的顺序。
So this is a bound.
所以这是必然的。
This is a slightly tighter bound.
这是一个更严格的界限。
We have a different solution to the problem.
对于这个问题，我们有不同的解决方案。
All the possible solutions are hard to argue.
所有可能的解决方案都很难争论。
They all come down to something like this.
他们都归结为这样的事情。
The one that we have requires you to use-- you
我们拥有的一个要求您使用-您
have two indices, and you know that the sum of the indices
有两个索引，您知道这些索引的总和
is k, and you do binary search on the top
是k，然后在顶部进行二进制搜索
and adjust the index on the bottom
并调整底部的索引
to keep the constraint that the sum of the two indices in N.
保持两个索引之和为N的约束。
And you can look at that in the notes that we're going to post.
您可以在我们将要发布的注释中进行查看。
Are you guys tired?
你们累了吗？
Do you want to look at one more thing, or are we done?
您是否要再看一件事，还是已经完成？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Let's look at something reasonably easy.
教授：让我们看一些比较容易的事情。
You guys can read this on your own.
你们可以自己阅读。
I'm not going to bore you with that.
我不会为此感到无聊。
So suppose we have some functions,
因此，假设我们有一些功能，
and we want to order them according
我们想根据他们订购
to their asymptotic growth rate.
渐近增长率。
Do people remember how to do this from Pset one?
人们还记得如何从Pset one中做到这一点吗？
So the idea is that you take each function, you simplify it,
因此，我们的想法是，您可以采用每个功能，对其进行简化，
and then you sort them.
然后对它们进行排序。
So let's have a couple of simple ones and then some hard ones,
因此，让我们先简单几个，然后再艰难一些，
and we're going to stop in five minutes.
我们将在五分钟内停止。
What's this?
这是什么？
AUDIENCE: n to the fourth.
听众：n至第四。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
n choose 3.
n选择3。
What is this?
这是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, very good.
教授：好的，很好。
Why?
为什么？
AUDIENCE: Something about choose is n times n minus 1 times
听众：选择的东西是n倍n减1倍
n minus 2.
n减2。
AUDIENCE: It's n factorial over n minus 2 factorial.
听众：n阶乘n减去2阶乘。
PROFESSOR: This comes out to be roughly n cubed.
教授：这大概是n立方的。
Cool.
凉。
How about n plus log to the fourth of n?
n加log到n的第四位怎么样？
AUDIENCE: N.
听众：N.
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So even if I have a polynomial in a logarithm,
所以即使我有一个对数的多项式
it's still dominated by pure n.
它仍然以纯n为主。
Now, suppose we want to order these guys together
现在，假设我们要一起订购这些家伙
with-- which one doesn't look boring at all?
与-哪一个看起来一点都不无聊？
n to the log n and 2 to the n.
n表示对数n，2表示n。
Let's sort them.
让我们对它们进行排序。
Which one's the smallest?
哪一个最小？
Which one's the biggest?
哪个最大？
AUDIENCE: 2 to the n is bigger.
听众：2到n更大。
PROFESSOR: Let's start with the smallest ones,
教授：让我们从最小的开始吧，
because I think that will be easy.
因为我认为这很容易。
So which one's the absolute smallest out of all these guys?
那么，在所有这些人中，哪个绝对是最小的？
AUDIENCE: n.
听众：
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Then?
然后？
AUDIENCE: n to the third.
听众：n至第三。
PROFESSOR: Cubed and fourth.
教授：立方，第四。
So we have to compare these guys.
所以我们必须比较这些家伙。
How do we compare them?
我们如何比较它们？
n to the power of log n and 2 to the n something.
n为对数n的幂，2为n的幂。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Take the logs.
教授：记录日志。
So when we have something confusing with exponentials,
因此，当我们对指数感到困惑时，
take the logs and see what we get.
记录日志，看看我们得到了什么。
Logs are monotonic, so if you take the logs,
日志是单调的，因此，如果您使用日志，
you'll have the same relationship afterwards.
之后您将拥有相同的关系。
So log of this is log of n to the power of log n,
因此，这的对数就是n的对数乘以log n的乘方，
so it's log n times log n, so it's log 2 n.
因此它是log n乘以log n，所以它是log 2 n。
Log of 2 to the n is n.
2到n的对数为n。
Which one's bigger?
哪个更大？
AUDIENCE: n.
听众：
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
And we're not going to solve this,
而且我们不会解决这个问题，
but how would you go about solving this guy?
但是您将如何解决这个人？
What do you do to it?
你是怎么做的？
AUDIENCE: Sterling.
观众：英镑。
PROFESSOR: Sterling, yep.
教授：斯特林，是的。
You do Sterling, you go through the numbers,
你做斯特林，你遍历数字，
and you figure out the answer.
然后您找出答案。
And then if you have to do logarithms,
然后如果您必须做对数，
you use logarithms to figure out where
你用对数找出
it belongs among these guys.
它属于这些人。
AUDIENCE: What's Sterling?
听众：什么是英镑？
AUDIENCE: Sterling's formula.
听众：斯特林的公式。
It's that gross thing that was on the board
董事会上的事情就是这样
before we came in here.
在我们来到这里之前。
PROFESSOR: So Sterling says that n factorial is ugly.
教授：所以斯特林说n阶乘是丑陋的。
2 pi n here times n over e to the power of n.
2 pi n在这里，n乘以e等于n的幂。
So what's this binomial?
那么这个二项式是什么？
What's the formula for it?
它的公式是什么？
OK, formula for n choose k.
OK，n的公式选择k。
Anyone?
任何人？
AUDIENCE: It's n times 1 over 2 factorial times n
听众：n是2阶乘n中的n倍
minus k factorial.
减去k阶乘。
PROFESSOR: In this case, it's n factorial
教授：在这种情况下，n是阶乘
over n over 2 factorial raised to the power of 2, right?
超过2的n个阶乘提高到2的幂，对吗？
And then we chug through the math and get to some answer.
然后我们学习数学并得出一些答案。
All right?
好吧？